<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"><channel><title>reStructuredText on Jürgen Gmach</title><link>https://jugmac00.github.io/tags/restructuredtext/</link><description>Recent content in reStructuredText on Jürgen Gmach</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Mon, 10 Jul 2023 18:10:41 +0200</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://jugmac00.github.io/tags/restructuredtext/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Anonymous Hyperlinks</title><link>https://jugmac00.github.io/til/anonymous-hyperlinks/</link><pubDate>Mon, 10 Jul 2023 18:10:41 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://jugmac00.github.io/til/anonymous-hyperlinks/</guid><description>Today, I looked something up in our documentation, and noticed an unformatted link.
`launchpad-mojo-specs &amp;lt;https://code.launchpad.net/launchpad-mojo-specs&amp;gt;` This is reStructuredText - a file format for structured data. While many people have switched to MarkDown, which is unarguably easier to read and write, I still like reStructuredText as it is very powerful.
The above link does not get rendered as a hyperlink, as it misses a trailing underscore.
I was about to add it, and directly commit, but luckily I tried to render it first.</description></item><item><title>How to Render a Single ReStructuredText Document</title><link>https://jugmac00.github.io/til/how-to-render-a-single-restructuredtext-document/</link><pubDate>Sat, 07 May 2022 14:35:22 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://jugmac00.github.io/til/how-to-render-a-single-restructuredtext-document/</guid><description>Today I came across ubuntu-archive-tools which is a great set of scripts to help administer the Ubuntu archive.
The project consists of Python scripts only, is not packaged, and the repository comes with no setup documentation.
After I have figured out which dependencies the project needs, I wanted to add a minimal documentation, so the next user has an easier start.
So, I created a README.rst, added some information&amp;hellip; and huh, how would I render the file locally to make sure I have not messed up the syntax?</description></item></channel></rss>