<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"><channel><title>Jürgen Gmach</title><link>https://jugmac00.github.io/</link><description>Recent content on Jürgen Gmach</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Sat, 22 May 2021 14:02:09 +0200</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://jugmac00.github.io/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Variable Scope and List Comprehensions</title><link>https://jugmac00.github.io/til/variable-scope-and-list-comprehensions/</link><pubDate>Sat, 22 May 2021 14:02:09 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://jugmac00.github.io/til/variable-scope-and-list-comprehensions/</guid><description>Python 2 In Python 2 the temporary variable was not so temporary at all&amp;hellip;
❯ python2 Python 2.7.17 (default, Feb 27 2021, 15:10:58) [GCC 7.5.0] on linux2 Type &amp;#34;help&amp;#34;, &amp;#34;copyright&amp;#34;, &amp;#34;credits&amp;#34; or &amp;#34;license&amp;#34; for more information. &amp;gt;&amp;gt;&amp;gt; s = &amp;#34;abc&amp;#34; &amp;gt;&amp;gt;&amp;gt; [x for x in s] [&amp;#39;a&amp;#39;, &amp;#39;b&amp;#39;, &amp;#39;c&amp;#39;] &amp;gt;&amp;gt;&amp;gt; x &amp;#39;c&amp;#39; As you can see, x leaks outside the scope the list comprehension.
Python 3 This has been changed in Python 3.</description></item><item><title>Enrich Test Coverage With Contexts</title><link>https://jugmac00.github.io/blog/enrich-test-coverage-with-contexts/</link><pubDate>Thu, 20 May 2021 14:22:51 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://jugmac00.github.io/blog/enrich-test-coverage-with-contexts/</guid><description>Hold on tight, now I expect a lot of us:
We all
test our code use coverage strive for 100% test coverage So, what&amp;rsquo;s missing?
I miss some context 100% test coverage is great, but sometimes we need more information.
e.g. which test covers line XXX?
In sufficiently complex code bases, with mixed unit and integration tests, this is no longer easy to find out.
Sure, you can set a breakpoint and run your tests and wait until the breakpoint has been hit.</description></item><item><title>Hugo and GitHub Pages - Welcome in the Land of Confusion</title><link>https://jugmac00.github.io/blog/hugo-and-github-pages-welcome-in-the-land-of-confusion/</link><pubDate>Wed, 12 May 2021 10:31:30 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://jugmac00.github.io/blog/hugo-and-github-pages-welcome-in-the-land-of-confusion/</guid><description>Yesterday, I migrated my blog to Hugo.
GitHub Pages While the migration was straight forward, I was a bit puzzled with the deployment process to GitHub.
For those who don&amp;rsquo;t know yet, GitHub enables all users to have an own website, called GitHub Pages, with a URL like https://your-user-name.github.io.
Previously I used Lektor. The source code for my site lived in https://github.com/jugmac00/jugmac00.github.io.source, and was deployed by Lektor to https://github.com/jugmac00/jugmac00.github.io.
Easy enough.</description></item><item><title>How to Create an Empty Git Branch</title><link>https://jugmac00.github.io/til/how-to-create-an-empty-git-branch/</link><pubDate>Wed, 12 May 2021 08:05:30 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://jugmac00.github.io/til/how-to-create-an-empty-git-branch/</guid><description>What do I mean by an empty branch?
Simply, a branch with no commits.
Why on earth&amp;hellip; Why would one even need an empty branch?
There are not many reasons which come to my mind, but imagine you start a rewrite of an existing project, and you want to start from scratch, but you want to keep the rewrite in the same repository.
For example tox does this:
the current main version is on master the upcoming version 4, which is a complete rewrite, is on the rewrite branch.</description></item><item><title>Bite My Shiny Type Annotated Library</title><link>https://jugmac00.github.io/blog/bite-my-shiny-type-annotated-library/</link><pubDate>Sun, 09 May 2021 15:40:11 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://jugmac00.github.io/blog/bite-my-shiny-type-annotated-library/</guid><description>How do you make type annotations available to the users of your library?
Well, you just type annotate your library, right?
No!
But let&amp;rsquo;s step back for a moment.
Flask 2.0 goes full type annotations This morning I read David Lord&amp;rsquo;s announcement that Flask, Jinja, Click, Werkzeug, MarkupSafe, and ItsDangerous are now fully type annotated, and new releases will be available next week.
Ok, as I typed Flask-Reuploaded almost a year ago, I certainly noticed that Flask was not typed back then, but external type information was provided via typeshed, which I remember lively, as I had to add a missing type annotation for Werkzeug.</description></item><item><title>How Can You Reclaim Some Disk Space From Docker</title><link>https://jugmac00.github.io/til/how-can-you-reclaim-some-disk-space-from-docker/</link><pubDate>Wed, 05 May 2021 22:00:13 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://jugmac00.github.io/til/how-can-you-reclaim-some-disk-space-from-docker/</guid><description>If you use Docker containers, and who doesn&amp;rsquo;t these times, you need to take care that Docker does not accumulate a lot of cruft.
remains of docker run If you start a container via docker run, and without the highly recommended option --rm, the exited Docker container will still leave some remains on your system.
In my case oO&amp;hellip;
❯ docker ps -a CONTAINER ID IMAGE COMMAND CREATED STATUS PORTS NAMES c14c0bd0d850 jetbrains/youtrack:2020.</description></item><item><title>What Is the Meaning of Dollar Dollar in Bash</title><link>https://jugmac00.github.io/til/what-is-the-meaning-of-dollar-dollar-in-bash/</link><pubDate>Fri, 30 Apr 2021 18:58:07 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://jugmac00.github.io/til/what-is-the-meaning-of-dollar-dollar-in-bash/</guid><description>I stumbled upon a colleague&amp;rsquo;s bash script which contained the following line, which in isolation, made not much sense to me.
WRKDIR=~/app/work$$ But after some googling and having a look at the complete scope of the script, I finally got it.
... WRKDIR=~/app/work$$ ... mkdir $WRKDIR ... ... ... ... rmdir $WRKDIR $$ is a reference to the PID (process id) it was used to create a unique temporary file All good?</description></item><item><title>How to Run a Bash Script in a Sane Way</title><link>https://jugmac00.github.io/til/how-to-run-a-bash-script-in-a-sane-way/</link><pubDate>Thu, 29 Apr 2021 18:48:26 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://jugmac00.github.io/til/how-to-run-a-bash-script-in-a-sane-way/</guid><description>When you never had problems with running/debugging a bash script, you might wonder what I am talking about.
Instead of introducing the possible problems, and then the way to counter them, let&amp;rsquo;s start with the solution.
All your bash scripts should probably start with&amp;hellip;
#!/usr/bin/env bash &amp;hellip; wait&amp;hellip; it goes on&amp;hellip;
set -euxo pipefail Wat? Ok, let&amp;rsquo;s go through the options, one by one.
set -e This makes a bash script to stop on error immediately, and exit.</description></item><item><title>How to Configure a Webserver to Be Less Secure</title><link>https://jugmac00.github.io/til/how-to-configure-a-webserver-to-be-less-secure/</link><pubDate>Thu, 29 Apr 2021 11:43:48 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://jugmac00.github.io/til/how-to-configure-a-webserver-to-be-less-secure/</guid><description>This question sounds odd. Why would you want a less secure web server?
Well, maybe you have to support older clients.
e.g. IE 11 on Windows 8.1 or Java 7 (cough) cannot connect to a web server, which only uses modern and secure ciphers.
From a Java application, which cannot be updated, but has to work, I got the following exception:
Exception in thread &amp;#34;main&amp;#34; javax.net.ssl.SSLHandshakeException: Received fatal alert: handshake_failure at sun.</description></item><item><title>How to Globally Gitignore Configuration Files</title><link>https://jugmac00.github.io/til/how-to-globally-gitignore-configuration-files/</link><pubDate>Tue, 27 Apr 2021 08:51:48 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://jugmac00.github.io/til/how-to-globally-gitignore-configuration-files/</guid><description>Until today, I did not make up my mind about what to do with configuration files, created by e.g. VS Code.
Certainly, I do not want to commit them, but putting it into every&amp;rsquo;s repository .gitignore file is also cumbersome - and sometimes it is not possible.
I always do a git add -u to avoid accidentally adding a venv or similar, so it did not really matter.
Except&amp;hellip;
❯ .</description></item><item><title>How Many Zope Repositories Are Compatible With Pypy?</title><link>https://jugmac00.github.io/til/how-many-zope-repositories-are-compatible-with-pypy/</link><pubDate>Mon, 19 Apr 2021 11:38:06 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://jugmac00.github.io/til/how-many-zope-repositories-are-compatible-with-pypy/</guid><description>Today, Johannes Raggam asked on the Plone/Zope community forum whether Zope is able to run on PyPy.
While I am not entirely sure, and I have some vague memories about potential problems with RestrictedPython, I can certainly grep the almost 300 Zope repositories for signs of PyPy support.
The best sign of PyPy support is IMHO that we run tests for it :-)
In order to grep in all repositories I use all-repos written by Anthony Sottile.</description></item><item><title>How to List All Open Pull Requests for One GitHub Organization</title><link>https://jugmac00.github.io/til/how-to-list-all-open-pull-requests-for-one-github-organization/</link><pubDate>Mon, 19 Apr 2021 09:03:29 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://jugmac00.github.io/til/how-to-list-all-open-pull-requests-for-one-github-organization/</guid><description>While most developers probably know, that you can list all your open pull requests on GitHub via https://github.com/pulls, how can you list all open pull requests for one GitHub organization?
I was on holiday for two weeks, and I want to get up to speed which pull requests need to be reviewed in my company&amp;hellip;
Luckily, there is no need to do a complicate query or work with GitHub&amp;rsquo;s GraphQL API&amp;hellip;</description></item><item><title>How to Capitalize Headings</title><link>https://jugmac00.github.io/til/how-to-capitalize-headings/</link><pubDate>Sat, 17 Apr 2021 11:23:37 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://jugmac00.github.io/til/how-to-capitalize-headings/</guid><description>Especially in English texts&amp;hellip;
I am no native English speaker, and there are so many subtleties in the English language, so when I was about to prepare my lightning talk submissions for both PyOhio and PyCon US, I was super happy that my friend Miroslav Šedivý sent me the following link:
https://capitalizemytitle.com/
At this site you can just paste your heading&amp;rsquo;s text, and you receive it properly capitalized, even in different styles, e.</description></item><item><title>How to Replace an URL in All Repositories</title><link>https://jugmac00.github.io/til/how-to-replace-url-in-all-repositories/</link><pubDate>Tue, 06 Apr 2021 11:22:11 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://jugmac00.github.io/til/how-to-replace-url-in-all-repositories/</guid><description>Recently Anthony Sottile, one of the maintainers of Flake8, announced on Twitter that the source code repository of Flake8 was moved from GitLab to GitHub.
Those of us, who also use Anthony&amp;rsquo;s pre-commit, now should update their .pre-commit-config.yaml file.
Though there is no hurry, as the repository on GitLab will stay as a mirror.
For one of my repos the .pre-config-config.yaml looks like this:
repos: ... - repo: https://gitlab.com/pycqa/flake8 rev: 3.</description></item><item><title>How to Restrict All Repos Grep to Specific Files</title><link>https://jugmac00.github.io/til/how-to-restrict-all-repos-grep-to-specific-files/</link><pubDate>Mon, 29 Mar 2021 18:42:46 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://jugmac00.github.io/til/how-to-restrict-all-repos-grep-to-specific-files/</guid><description>Back at the end of 2020, when Travis announced you need to move your open source projects from https://travis-ci.org to https://travis-ci.com, I wanted to know in which README files I used the link to the org-site - of the many, many repositories I manage.
That is a textbook example what you can do with all-repos.
A naive way would be to grep in all repositories like &amp;hellip;
all-repos-grep travis-ci.org Instead of grepping in all files, it is a better idea to restrict the search to only README files.</description></item><item><title>How to Find Duplicate Words</title><link>https://jugmac00.github.io/til/how-to-find-duplicate-words/</link><pubDate>Wed, 24 Mar 2021 11:05:58 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://jugmac00.github.io/til/how-to-find-duplicate-words/</guid><description>When contributing to a new open source project, from time to time I searched the codebase for occurrences of the the.
This is a common mistake in comments in English codebases.
My friend Miroslav came up with an even better way:
Use a regex to find duplicate words!
rg --pcre2 &amp;#34;\b(\w+)\s+\1\b&amp;#34; rg stands for ripgrep, which is a blazing fast implementation of a regex command line tool, written in Rust.</description></item><item><title>How to Fix a Broken Rollback on Nixos, caused by mixed Python Environments</title><link>https://jugmac00.github.io/til/how-to-fix-broken-rollback-on-nixos/</link><pubDate>Tue, 23 Mar 2021 19:14:44 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://jugmac00.github.io/til/how-to-fix-broken-rollback-on-nixos/</guid><description>Today I tried to update a Nixos channel to 20.09.xxx, but the virtual machine was still running on 15.09, and seemingly the nix-version was pinned.
I got an error saying something like the nix version is too low.
I then tried to do a rollback, but then I got another following error:
ERROR: ./batou --help Return code: 1 STDOUT Running unclean installation from requirements.txt Ensuring unclean install ... .batou/unclean/bin/python -m pip install -r requirements.</description></item><item><title>How to Find All Repositories in a GitHub Organization Which Do Not Follow the Src Layout?</title><link>https://jugmac00.github.io/til/how-to-find-all-repositories-which-do-not-follow-src-layout/</link><pubDate>Fri, 05 Mar 2021 10:49:56 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://jugmac00.github.io/til/how-to-find-all-repositories-which-do-not-follow-src-layout/</guid><description>Let&amp;rsquo;s say, while not everybody is convinced, that the so-called src layout is a great idea, at least it is a trend in the Python eco system.
And, e.g. Hynek has written about good reasons to use the src layout.
While my personal and work repositories (mostly) follow the src layout, what about the almost 300 Zope repositories?
all-repos to the rescue I really love to play with all-repos, an awesome tool to manage and manipulate a large amount of git repositories.</description></item><item><title>Testing the tox 4 Pre-Release at Scale</title><link>https://jugmac00.github.io/blog/testing-the-tox-4-pre-release-at-scale/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Mar 2021 15:31:06 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://jugmac00.github.io/blog/testing-the-tox-4-pre-release-at-scale/</guid><description>Every once in a while, you may read that one of your favorite used packages announces a new version.
Sometimes even a so-called alpha version is announced.
The maintainers then politely ask you, the user, to test the package, and give feedback if anything is broken.
When the upcoming pytest version 6 had been announced, I wrote a short instruction on how to install pre-releases.
This time, tox, the virtualenv management and test tool, announced a new version 4, but it is not just a new version, it is a complete rewrite by Bernát Gábor!</description></item><item><title>How to Restrict All Repos to One Github Organization</title><link>https://jugmac00.github.io/til/how-to-restrict-all-repos-to-one-github-organization/</link><pubDate>Thu, 25 Feb 2021 16:36:50 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://jugmac00.github.io/til/how-to-restrict-all-repos-to-one-github-organization/</guid><description>Especially, when maintaining many, many git repositories at once, Anthony Sottile&amp;rsquo;s all-repos is a bliss.
You can easily grep for text or find files in, or even apply patches to hundreds or thousands of repositories at once, which I already described in a blog post.
all-repos has a configuration option, which allows you to clone and manage all of your GitHub repositories at once.
Mine looks like&amp;hellip;
{ &amp;#34;output_dir&amp;#34;: &amp;#34;output&amp;#34;, &amp;#34;source&amp;#34;: &amp;#34;all_repos.</description></item><item><title>How to Check the Expiry Date of an SSL/TLS Certificate</title><link>https://jugmac00.github.io/til/how-to-check-the-expiry-date-of-ssl-certificate/</link><pubDate>Mon, 22 Feb 2021 11:37:24 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://jugmac00.github.io/til/how-to-check-the-expiry-date-of-ssl-certificate/</guid><description>For a couple of years now, I use the fantastic (and free*) service by Let&amp;rsquo;s Encrypt in order to generate SSL/TLS certificates.
One of the main differences to paid certs is that the ones of Let&amp;rsquo;s Encrypt are only valid 90 days.
This sounds bad at first, but actually this is a good thing from a security perspective, and anyway, you do not create / renew certs manually, but one of the many clients do this for you automatically.</description></item><item><title>How to Update All Installed Rust Packages</title><link>https://jugmac00.github.io/til/how-to-update-all-installed-rust-packages/</link><pubDate>Mon, 22 Feb 2021 11:10:14 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://jugmac00.github.io/til/how-to-update-all-installed-rust-packages/</guid><description>Rust is not only known for its memory safety, but also for being (almost) on par with C, speed-wise.
In the last couple of years quite some interesting tools were created, which may replace common Linux command line tools, e.g. bat instead of cat, ripgrep instead of grep, &amp;hellip;
I installed a handful of them via cargo, Rust&amp;rsquo;s package manager.
I can list all packages with cargo install --list &amp;hellip;</description></item><item><title>How Can You Convert an Adobe Illustrator File (AI) to an Encapsulated Postscript File (eps)</title><link>https://jugmac00.github.io/til/how-can-you-convert-an-adobe-illustrator-file-to-an-encapsulated-postscript-file/</link><pubDate>Tue, 19 Jan 2021 22:23:23 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://jugmac00.github.io/til/how-can-you-convert-an-adobe-illustrator-file-to-an-encapsulated-postscript-file/</guid><description>One of my web applications is using RML to render PDFs.
For one PDF document template I received a new logo file which was produced with Adobe Illustrator (file extension .ai).
The RML library cannot handle ai-files, but eps-files.
In order to convert the file I used Ghostscript as following:
gs -dNOPAUSE -dBATCH -sDEVICE=eps2write -sOutputFile=out.eps input.ai where
-dNOPAUSE means &amp;ldquo;no pause after page&amp;rdquo; -dBATCH means &amp;ldquo;exit after last file&amp;rdquo; -sDEVICE selects the device -sOutputFile is the name of the - you can guess it - output file P.</description></item><item><title>Which Image Formats Are Supported by ReportLab's PDF Library</title><link>https://jugmac00.github.io/til/which-image-formats-are-supported-by-reportlabs-pdf-library/</link><pubDate>Tue, 19 Jan 2021 11:00:45 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://jugmac00.github.io/til/which-image-formats-are-supported-by-reportlabs-pdf-library/</guid><description>ReportLab is an open source library for generating PDFs, written in Python.
While ReportLab is absolutely battle tested, even Wikipedia uses it for PDF generation, documentation lacks a bit.
I could not find a reliable source for supported image formats.
Also, there is both an open source and a commercial license for ReportLab, with different feature sets. The latter one is supposed to be able to treat PDFs as image files, which then can be embedded.</description></item><item><title>How to Install a Python Package Directly From a Git Branch From GitHub</title><link>https://jugmac00.github.io/til/how-to-install-a-python-package-directly-from-a-git-branch-from-github/</link><pubDate>Mon, 11 Jan 2021 08:55:54 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://jugmac00.github.io/til/how-to-install-a-python-package-directly-from-a-git-branch-from-github/</guid><description>Bernát Gábor is currently working on a complete rewrite for tox.
I alpha-tested the latest release (4.0.0a2), and reported a couple of problems.
Within a day Bernát published some fixes on the rewrite branch, and asked me to test it.
That means there is no new package on PyPI, yet.
So, I had to install tox directly from GitHub, to be exact, from the rewrite branch:
pip install git+https://github.com/tox-dev/tox@rewrite or more general</description></item><item><title>How to Check Support Status for Installed Packages</title><link>https://jugmac00.github.io/til/how-to-check-support-status-for-installed-packages/</link><pubDate>Fri, 04 Dec 2020 12:00:13 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://jugmac00.github.io/til/how-to-check-support-status-for-installed-packages/</guid><description>When you install a package from the package repository on Ubuntu LTS, the package will be maintained for 5 years, right?
No!
At least, not necessarily.
Basically, you need to understand that there are different repository types for Ubuntu:
type maintained by canonical floss guaranteed support in years main yes yes 5 restricted yes no ? universe no yes ?</description></item><item><title>What Is the Difference Between Invoking `pytest` and `python -m pytest`</title><link>https://jugmac00.github.io/til/what-is-the-difference-between-invoking-pytest-and-python-m-pytest/</link><pubDate>Thu, 03 Dec 2020 09:16:51 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://jugmac00.github.io/til/what-is-the-difference-between-invoking-pytest-and-python-m-pytest/</guid><description>Yesterday, I was recommended to have a look at Shopyo - Open inventory management and Point of sales.
As I am passionate about testing and CI, I always have a look at configuration files for newly discovered projects.
After I cloned the repository, I tried to run the tests.
So, without having a look into the documentation ( :-/ ), I
created a virtual env installed the dependencies ran pytest from the root of the project &amp;hellip; and got a ModuleNotFoundError The friendly maintainers of the projects pointed me in the right direction on how to run tests for this project:</description></item><item><title>How to Configure Git for Testing</title><link>https://jugmac00.github.io/til/how-to-configure-git-for-testing/</link><pubDate>Mon, 16 Nov 2020 07:01:19 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://jugmac00.github.io/til/how-to-configure-git-for-testing/</guid><description>batou is a configuration management and deployment tool, comparable to Ansible.
With batou you can deploy applications, also from git repositories.
For this batou uses the git binary - so this has to be tested somehow.
One test looks like this&amp;hellip;
def test_git_remote_init_pull(tmpdir): source = tmpdir.mkdir(&amp;#34;source&amp;#34;) dest = tmpdir.mkdir(&amp;#34;dest&amp;#34;) with source.as_cwd(): remote_core.cmd(&amp;#34;git init&amp;#34;) source.join(&amp;#34;foo.txt&amp;#34;).write(&amp;#34;bar&amp;#34;) remote_core.cmd(&amp;#34;git add foo.txt&amp;#34;) remote_core.cmd(&amp;#34;git commit -m bar&amp;#34;) remote_core.ensure_repository(str(dest), &amp;#34;git-bundle&amp;#34;) remote_core.git_pull_code(str(source), &amp;#34;master&amp;#34;) remote_core.git_update_working_copy(&amp;#34;master&amp;#34;) assert &amp;#34;bar&amp;#34; == dest.join(&amp;#34;foo.txt&amp;#34;).read() &amp;hellip; and worked in some environments, even on Travis, but failed on my Ubuntu box, and later also on GH Actions:</description></item><item><title>How to Group Data Easily With Simplenamespace</title><link>https://jugmac00.github.io/til/how-to-group-data-easily-with-simplenamespace/</link><pubDate>Fri, 13 Nov 2020 09:24:27 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://jugmac00.github.io/til/how-to-group-data-easily-with-simplenamespace/</guid><description>While you could use the usual suspects, like a dictionary, a NamedTuple, a dataclass, or even an &amp;ldquo;empty&amp;rdquo; class, there is yet another way: SimpleNamespace.
&amp;gt;&amp;gt;&amp;gt; from types import SimpleNamespace &amp;gt;&amp;gt;&amp;gt; simple_ns = SimpleNamespace(a=1, b=&amp;#34;two&amp;#34;) &amp;gt;&amp;gt;&amp;gt; simple_ns namespace(a=1, b=&amp;#39;two&amp;#39;) &amp;gt;&amp;gt;&amp;gt; simple_ns.a 1 &amp;gt;&amp;gt;&amp;gt; simple_ns.b &amp;#39;two&amp;#39; &amp;gt;&amp;gt;&amp;gt; implementation This builtin is implemented in C, but the Python docs show how it would look like in Python:
class SimpleNamespace: def __init__(self, /, **kwargs): self.</description></item><item><title>Convincing an Enterprisy App to Work Behind nginx as Reverse Proxy</title><link>https://jugmac00.github.io/blog/convincing-an-enterprisy-app-to-work-behind-nginx-as-reverse-proxy/</link><pubDate>Fri, 30 Oct 2020 15:26:14 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://jugmac00.github.io/blog/convincing-an-enterprisy-app-to-work-behind-nginx-as-reverse-proxy/</guid><description>For simplicity, let&amp;rsquo;s the call the app Dated HR, a tool to &amp;ldquo;Simplify your HR work&amp;rdquo;, which offers support for time tracking, holiday, payroll&amp;hellip;
So far so good, and even better, as it is an enterprisy Windows software, which needs to be configured with IIS and a MSSQL database, a colleague of mine installed it on an internal Windows server.
The app makes a web GUI available under http://nemesis.company.local, which would work like a charm - for our colleagues at site, but not for the colleagues from the other sites.</description></item><item><title>How to Fix Broken Tests on Travis for PyPy</title><link>https://jugmac00.github.io/til/how-to-fix-broken-tests-on-travis-for-pypy/</link><pubDate>Fri, 30 Oct 2020 11:57:42 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://jugmac00.github.io/til/how-to-fix-broken-tests-on-travis-for-pypy/</guid><description>The xenial build of pypy on Travis CI links against OpenSSL 1.0.2, which causes pip install cryptography to fail with
RuntimeError: You are linking against OpenSSL 1.0.2, which is no longer supported by the OpenSSL project. To use this version of cryptography you need to upgrade to a newer version of OpenSSL. For this version only you can also set the environment variable CRYPTOGRAPHY_ALLOW_OPENSSL_102 to allow OpenSSL 1.0.2. Marius found the solution, see https://github.</description></item><item><title>What Is the Difference Between Docker Create, Docker Start and Docker Run</title><link>https://jugmac00.github.io/til/what-is-the-difference-between-docker-create-docker-start-and-docker-run/</link><pubDate>Thu, 29 Oct 2020 21:56:22 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://jugmac00.github.io/til/what-is-the-difference-between-docker-create-docker-start-and-docker-run/</guid><description>In order to be able to answer this question, you have to know that there are
Docker images Docker containers Docker images are blueprints or templates.
Docker containers are the instances, created from the images.
docker create creates a container from an image
docker start starts a container
docker run creates a container and starts it
note Trying to use the run command twice results in something like&amp;hellip;</description></item><item><title>How to Run a Dockerized Service via systemd</title><link>https://jugmac00.github.io/blog/how-to-run-a-dockerized-service-via-systemd/</link><pubDate>Thu, 29 Oct 2020 15:18:40 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://jugmac00.github.io/blog/how-to-run-a-dockerized-service-via-systemd/</guid><description>Until recently, I saw no good reason to use Docker, as my deployment tool of choice produces approximately identical builds, locally on my Ubuntu laptop, on staging and on production.
But time does not stand still and especially as I have to deploy a Java application, it was time to rethink my strategy, as I do not want to play the which Java runtime environment plays nicely together with which app version game.</description></item><item><title>How to Create Hundreds of Pull Requests With a Single Command</title><link>https://jugmac00.github.io/blog/how-to-create-hundreds-of-pull-requests-with-a-single-command/</link><pubDate>Wed, 28 Oct 2020 15:02:44 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://jugmac00.github.io/blog/how-to-create-hundreds-of-pull-requests-with-a-single-command/</guid><description>.. or &amp;ldquo;How to win #hacktoberfest&amp;rdquo;?
Seriously&amp;hellip;
#hacktoberfest is no longer cool ( Hacktoberfest is Hurting Open Source ) you cannot win it anyway the mass pull requests I created (see below) went all to repositories, which do not take part at #hacktoberfest note If you are not interested in the story behind, I also created a concise &amp;ldquo;today-I-learned&amp;rdquo; post.
prologue The company I work for has been using Zope, the grand-daddy of Python web application servers, for more than 15 years.</description></item><item><title>How to Use the Output of One Bash Command as the Argument of Another</title><link>https://jugmac00.github.io/til/how-to-use-the-output-of-one-bash-command-as-the-argument-of-another/</link><pubDate>Mon, 07 Sep 2020 18:52:25 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://jugmac00.github.io/til/how-to-use-the-output-of-one-bash-command-as-the-argument-of-another/</guid><description>TIL my TIL is not secure There is a security issue with the following description - at least when you handle sensitive data.
see here https://github.com/jugmac00/til/commit/7ea93202cecf97070c8931bbe5a1f64c78d41dcb#commitcomment-42050997
Thanks to Anthony Sottile for reporting!
Please see https://unix.stackexchange.com/questions/205180/how-to-pass-password-to-mysql-command-line for a better way to create a login one-liner.
How do you use the output of one bash command as an argument of another command? For the virtual machines at my web hosting company, the mysql root password is stored in a config file.</description></item><item><title>How Long Does Flask Keep User Generated Data</title><link>https://jugmac00.github.io/til/how-long-does-flask-keep-user-generated-data/</link><pubDate>Fri, 04 Sep 2020 22:06:32 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://jugmac00.github.io/til/how-long-does-flask-keep-user-generated-data/</guid><description>Easy!
Either Flask persists the data into a database or a file, or it does not.
Wait, not so fast. There is also
session scoped data (e.g. storing data in a cookie or similar) app scoped data (e.g. store data on the app object) The caveats
session scoped data is only available for one client, and as long the session lasts app scoped data is only available within a single app - usually, e.</description></item><item><title>How to Sort Files and Folders in Nautilus So Folders Are Shown First</title><link>https://jugmac00.github.io/til/how-to-sort-files-and-folders-in-nautilus-so-folders-are-shown-first/</link><pubDate>Tue, 25 Aug 2020 09:07:30 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://jugmac00.github.io/til/how-to-sort-files-and-folders-in-nautilus-so-folders-are-shown-first/</guid><description>update settings gsettings set org.gtk.Settings.FileChooser sort-directories-first true check settings gsettings get org.gtk.Settings.FileChooser sort-directories-first via https://askubuntu.com/questions/1064482/</description></item><item><title>How Can You Inject the Language as String Into a Jinja Template</title><link>https://jugmac00.github.io/til/how-can-you-inject-the-language-as-string-into-a-jinja-template/</link><pubDate>Thu, 13 Aug 2020 22:15:25 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://jugmac00.github.io/til/how-can-you-inject-the-language-as-string-into-a-jinja-template/</guid><description>I created a multilingual project using Flask with the help of Flask-Babel.
While the translation mechanism via GNU gettext itself is pretty straightforward, I did not know how to inject the actual language into the Jinja template, so I can use it to set &amp;lt;html lang=&amp;quot;xxx&amp;quot;&amp;gt;.
While it is odd that this is not mentioned in the documentation, once again StackOverflow offered solutions.
solution one Just translate the language!
&amp;lt;html lang=&amp;#34;{{ _(&amp;#39;en&amp;#39;) }}&amp;#34;&amp;gt; That was too simple to think of :-)</description></item><item><title>How to View Log Entries Using Systemd</title><link>https://jugmac00.github.io/til/how-to-view-log-entries-using-systemd/</link><pubDate>Mon, 10 Aug 2020 11:54:07 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://jugmac00.github.io/til/how-to-view-log-entries-using-systemd/</guid><description>Until very recently I was lucky enough to have real log files, but now I have to use systemd&amp;rsquo;s way to view logs.
show all log entries journalctl show nginx' log entries journalctl -u nginx directly jump to the latest entries journalctl -e -u nginx</description></item><item><title>How to Remove a File From a Git Repository but Keep It Locally</title><link>https://jugmac00.github.io/til/how-to-remove-a-file-from-a-git-repository-but-keep-it-locally/</link><pubDate>Mon, 10 Aug 2020 09:00:14 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://jugmac00.github.io/til/how-to-remove-a-file-from-a-git-repository-but-keep-it-locally/</guid><description>For a video project, I have a video folder with videos and subtitle files.
Obviously, I do not want to have hundreds of megabytes in my git repository, so I git ignored them - but I committed the subtitles.
Now, the videos and the subtitles will be served by nginx from a media directory, outside of the project.
In order to delete the subtitles from the git repository, but keep them locally, I have to&amp;hellip;</description></item><item><title>How to Fix an Old Git Commit</title><link>https://jugmac00.github.io/til/how-to-fix-an-old-git-commit/</link><pubDate>Mon, 10 Aug 2020 08:03:11 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://jugmac00.github.io/til/how-to-fix-an-old-git-commit/</guid><description>&amp;hellip; which you do not have pushed to a remote repository.
git add &amp;lt;my fixed files&amp;gt; git commit --fixup=OLDCOMMIT git rebase --interactive --autosquash OLDCOMMIT^ via https://twitter.com/nnja/status/796876898005417984?s=03 via https://stackoverflow.com/questions/2719579/how-to-add-a-changed-file-to-an-older-not-last-commit-in-git/27721031#27721031</description></item><item><title>How to Audit and Harden an SSH Client</title><link>https://jugmac00.github.io/til/how-to-audit-and-harden-an-ssh-client/</link><pubDate>Wed, 22 Jul 2020 11:30:28 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://jugmac00.github.io/til/how-to-audit-and-harden-an-ssh-client/</guid><description>You probably know how to harden an SSH server, or at least heard of it.
e.g. do not offer weak ciphers, or do not allow root login&amp;hellip;
But did you know you can and also should harden your SSH client?
step 1 - auditing your SSH client terminal 1 git clone https://github.com/jtesta/ssh-audit cd ssh-audit python3.8 ssh-audit.py -c # c = client audit; this starts a ssh server on port 2222 terminal 2 ssh localhost -p 2222 Now, switch back to terminal 1 and have a look at the output - it all should be green - but it won&amp;rsquo;t.</description></item><item><title>How to Find Nginx Config File on a Nixos Vm</title><link>https://jugmac00.github.io/til/how-to-find-nginx-config-file-on-a-nixos-vm/</link><pubDate>Wed, 15 Jul 2020 09:09:41 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://jugmac00.github.io/til/how-to-find-nginx-config-file-on-a-nixos-vm/</guid><description>Nixos&amp;hellip; hm, a dream for my web hosting company, but a nightmare as a casual user :-D
Compared to other Linux distributions, there are so many differences.
For a start&amp;hellip; where the heck is my nginx.conf? Hint - it is not in /etc/nginx/nginx.conf
systemctl cat nginx ... X-CheckConfigCmd=/nix/store/xxx-nginx-1.14.2/bin/nginx -t -c /nix/store/xxx-nginx.conf -p /var/spool/nginx X-ConfigFile=/nix/store/xxx-nginx.conf In order to show the configuration, FlyingCircus (my hosting company) created a custom command
nginx-show-config | less .</description></item><item><title>How to Access Name Based Servers in Development Setup</title><link>https://jugmac00.github.io/til/how-to-access-name-based-servers-in-development-setup/</link><pubDate>Mon, 13 Jul 2020 19:19:18 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://jugmac00.github.io/til/how-to-access-name-based-servers-in-development-setup/</guid><description>The problem You run a web application via nginx and you dispatch the requests based on the server name.
And maybe the server name header only gets set via a proxy or an URL, which is currently or permanent not available in your dev setup.
The solution curl -- header &amp;#34;Host: example.com&amp;#34; http://localhost Further information Blog post by the maintainer of curl:
https://daniel.haxx.se/blog/2018/04/05/curl-another-host/</description></item><item><title>How to List Packages Which Can Be Upgraded</title><link>https://jugmac00.github.io/til/how-to-list-packages-which-can-be-upgraded/</link><pubDate>Mon, 13 Jul 2020 13:04:41 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://jugmac00.github.io/til/how-to-list-packages-which-can-be-upgraded/</guid><description>Have you ever logged into your Ubuntu machine and you get greeted with xxx packages can be updated?
Do you want to know which packages can be updated before running apt upgrade?
This is for you (and me):
apt list --upgradable</description></item><item><title>How to Install Release Candidates</title><link>https://jugmac00.github.io/til/how-to-install-release-candidates/</link><pubDate>Fri, 10 Jul 2020 09:29:55 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://jugmac00.github.io/til/how-to-install-release-candidates/</guid><description>How to install release candidates Today on Twitter, one of the core maintainers of pytest announced the release of pytest 6.0.0rc1, and also asked to install and run it, and report if there are any problems. https://twitter.com/nicoddemus/status/1281385522422784005
Ok, but how do you install a release candidate?
If you just do a pip install pytest, the current latest release gets installed, which is 5.4.3 as the time of writing.
Turns out, there are a couple of options&amp;hellip;</description></item><item><title>Flask Reuploaded</title><link>https://jugmac00.github.io/blog/flask-reuploaded/</link><pubDate>Sun, 28 Jun 2020 14:27:13 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://jugmac00.github.io/blog/flask-reuploaded/</guid><description>It all started with this error message:
File &amp;#34;/Projects/xxx/venv/lib/python3.7/site-packages/flask_uploads.py&amp;#34;, line 26, in &amp;lt;module&amp;gt; from werkzeug import secure_filename, FileStorage ImportError: cannot import name &amp;#39;secure_filename&amp;#39; from &amp;#39;werkzeug&amp;#39;&amp;#39; Trying to build my Flask application, the above error message was generated, as Werkzeug, a very important library in the Flask ecosystem, changed its API in version 1.0, back in February 2020.
This broke a lot of plugins.
Twitter thread
As my app relies on Flask-Uploads, I had a look at the problem and finally provided a pull request to the Flask-Uploads repository on GitHub.</description></item><item><title>How to Deactivate Auto Import in Pylance</title><link>https://jugmac00.github.io/til/how-to-deactivate-auto-import-in-pylance/</link><pubDate>Sat, 06 Jun 2020 09:14:02 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://jugmac00.github.io/til/how-to-deactivate-auto-import-in-pylance/</guid><description>Unfortunately, the auto-import feature in PyLance surprised me with random imports.
e.g. with from unittest.case import expectedFailure just when I typed assert result == expected.
Luckily, the developers heard on the users, and with version 2020.8.0 this &amp;ldquo;feature&amp;rdquo; is optional.
In order to deactivate it, set the following option to false:
python.analysis.autoImportCompletions Thank you, Savannah!</description></item><item><title>Log Rotation for Python Applications - Without killing them softly</title><link>https://jugmac00.github.io/blog/log-rotation-for-python-applications/</link><pubDate>Wed, 08 Apr 2020 14:20:11 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://jugmac00.github.io/blog/log-rotation-for-python-applications/</guid><description>A couple of days after a successful deployment of my Zope 4 application, I noticed something worrisome.
Zope gets killed every night, shortly after midnight.
I use Supervisor, which monitors the process and restarts it, so that&amp;rsquo;s not the problem.
But there are two problems:
I did not trigger this on purpose. The cache of my app is cold, that means that my colleagues get slow response times for the first queries in the morning.</description></item><item><title>isort and pre-commit - a friendship with obstacles</title><link>https://jugmac00.github.io/blog/isort-and-pre-commit-a-friendship-with-obstacles/</link><pubDate>Sun, 23 Feb 2020 14:06:45 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://jugmac00.github.io/blog/isort-and-pre-commit-a-friendship-with-obstacles/</guid><description>Note This post is not intended to be an exhaustive introduction to pre-commit and its hooks. Please visit pre-commit.com for a complete documentation.
In a nutshell&amp;hellip;
pre-commit From its website:
A framework for managing and maintaining multi-language pre-commit hooks.
Very simplified this means, whenever you try to commit changes in your project (e.g. entering git commit), pre-commit runs all configured tools (e.g. linter, formatter, &amp;hellip;), and only if they run successfully, your commit will be executed - otherwise your commit will fail.</description></item><item><title>Three Ways to Get Into Trouble or Welcome Back PageTemplateEngine</title><link>https://jugmac00.github.io/blog/three-ways-to-get-into-trouble-or-welcome-back-pagetemplateengine/</link><pubDate>Tue, 26 Nov 2019 13:58:44 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://jugmac00.github.io/blog/three-ways-to-get-into-trouble-or-welcome-back-pagetemplateengine/</guid><description>The web application server Zope has a very long history which dates back to the late &amp;rsquo;90s.
Quoting Martijn Faassen:
Zope must be one of the oldest Python codebases in the world that is still used outside the standard library.
During its many years of existence the way a view gets rendered has changed.
Basically there are two supported template mechanisms:
Document Template Markup Language (DTML) Zope Page Templates (ZPT) DTML is pretty much outdated for more than a decade, but still in use for the Zope Management Interface.</description></item><item><title>Am I Famous</title><link>https://jugmac00.github.io/blog/am-i-famous/</link><pubDate>Wed, 29 May 2019 13:45:09 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://jugmac00.github.io/blog/am-i-famous/</guid><description>A couple of months ago, Brett Cannon, one of the better known Python core developers, announced on Twitter that he contributed to over 100 open source projects.
first reaction Woohah! Congratulations!
second reaction How did he know?
Everytime I get a PR merged I record the repo&amp;rsquo;s URL for a tool I created to analyze my contributions to OSS.
Ah&amp;hellip; k. I did not do that.
third reaction To how many open source projects did I contribute?</description></item><item><title>PyConWeb 2019: Came for the talks, stayed for the raffles</title><link>https://jugmac00.github.io/blog/pyconweb-2019/</link><pubDate>Mon, 27 May 2019 13:39:09 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://jugmac00.github.io/blog/pyconweb-2019/</guid><description>summary of pyconweb 2019 F&amp;hellip; awesome!
talks and workshops I tried to collect all slides from Twitter and Telegram - in case I missed some, please drop me a line @jugmac00.
Saturday, 25 May 2019 Building robust APIs Tornado Web Services on AsyncIO Bocadillo, or how I built an open source async web framework slides@Dropbox | slides@Github Introduction to GraphQL and Graphene source Hello to the World in 8 Web Frameworks slides and video @aaronbassett Life without passwords The dos and don&amp;rsquo;ts of task queues An introduction to D3.</description></item><item><title>Chrome No Longer Shows Saved Passwords</title><link>https://jugmac00.github.io/blog/chrome-no-longer-shows-saved-passwords/</link><pubDate>Fri, 10 May 2019 13:35:01 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://jugmac00.github.io/blog/chrome-no-longer-shows-saved-passwords/</guid><description>Concerning security and privacy, you either can get stalled because you can&amp;rsquo;t get it perfect right from the beginning, or you improve over time.
I prefer the latter one. And concerning password security I go with Troy Hunt: Password managers don&amp;rsquo;t have to be perfect, they just have to be better than not having one.
And actually the password manager of a browser is already a password manager. I would not use it for very important passwords, but it is absolutely fine for those dozens of dozens forum logins and so on.</description></item><item><title>Recap Day Three and Wrap Up of Zope Spring Cleaning</title><link>https://jugmac00.github.io/blog/recap-day-three-and-wrap-up-of-zope-spring-cleaning/</link><pubDate>Fri, 10 May 2019 13:27:31 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://jugmac00.github.io/blog/recap-day-three-and-wrap-up-of-zope-spring-cleaning/</guid><description>This blog post is work in progress&amp;hellip; much more to come - but the train is only 10 minutes late (uncommon in Germany :-) ), so I am not able finish the blog post now (narrator: he never has updated and never will update this blog post).
tl/dr - what a ride! today there was the final release of Zope 4! see blog post @gocept Michael / @gocept announced the roadmap for Zope 2.</description></item><item><title>Recap Day Two of Zope Spring Cleaning</title><link>https://jugmac00.github.io/blog/recap-day-two-of-zope-spring-cleaning/</link><pubDate>Fri, 10 May 2019 13:22:15 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://jugmac00.github.io/blog/recap-day-two-of-zope-spring-cleaning/</guid><description>Very brief recap, as I want to spend the remaining time with some more documentation updates.
progress Jens Hinghaus Fix bug in ZMI search improve tempstorage fix Steffen finished the documentation for the Nonsensical path issue had some fun with getting AppVeyor up and running for Zope Daniel fixed a bug in ZCatalog (sorting did not work); migrated a DTML template to zpt Jeremy continued his work on zc.</description></item><item><title>Recap day one of "Zope spring cleaning"</title><link>https://jugmac00.github.io/blog/recap-of-the-first-day-of-saltlabs-sprint-zope-spring-cleaning/</link><pubDate>Thu, 09 May 2019 13:14:12 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://jugmac00.github.io/blog/recap-of-the-first-day-of-saltlabs-sprint-zope-spring-cleaning/</guid><description>More infos about the sprint
10 local sprinters 2 remote sprinters (Jens Vagelpohl and Dieter Maurer) progress Steffen had lots of fun with Nonsensical Path Infos had a look at some of the open documentation tickets Jens Klein / Martin Häcker created a pull request to improve the zodpupdate script created / extracted plone/zodbverify which can be used to check ZODB before the Python 2 -&amp;gt; 3 migration Jeremy worked on porting recipe.</description></item><item><title>Face to face with "Earl Zope and his henchmen"</title><link>https://jugmac00.github.io/blog/face-to-face-with-earl-zope/</link><pubDate>Fri, 03 May 2019 12:48:11 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://jugmac00.github.io/blog/face-to-face-with-earl-zope/</guid><description>This blog post tries to ease beginning and keeping up with the development of the open source web application server Zope and its universe.
what makes it hard to start contributing Zope is a very mature product, as it was launched already back in 1999 Zope underwent some major architectural changes (keyword ZCA) Zope itself is relatively complex there is also a complex development ecosystem around it Buildout TravisCI (as of 2021, Travis is no longer used, but GHA) GitHub.</description></item><item><title>it's never too late to join the party!</title><link>https://jugmac00.github.io/blog/it-is-never-too-late-too-join-the-party/</link><pubDate>Thu, 02 May 2019 11:50:14 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://jugmac00.github.io/blog/it-is-never-too-late-too-join-the-party/</guid><description>Although I started writing code already at the age of 13 (generation C64), and I am a professional web and backend developer since 2007, I only started contributing to open source software quite recently - apart from the occasional bug report.
what is open source software? Quote from Wikipedia:
Open-source software (OSS) is a type of computer software in which source code is released under a license in which the copyright holder grants users the rights to study, change, and distribute the software to anyone and for any purpose.</description></item><item><title>ignore requests for apple touch icons</title><link>https://jugmac00.github.io/blog/ignore-requests-for-apple-touch-icons/</link><pubDate>Sat, 28 Jul 2018 11:38:38 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://jugmac00.github.io/blog/ignore-requests-for-apple-touch-icons/</guid><description>the problem My application&amp;rsquo;s error log is polluted with tracebacks of notFoundErrors from Apple browsers requesting apple-touch-icon.pngs.
For those, who do not know&amp;hellip; Touch icons are to Apple&amp;rsquo;s mobile devices what favicons are to (desktop) web browsers.
According to ComputerHope:
When someone bookmarks your web page or adds your web page to their home screen, this icon is used.
So, when you run a public website, no question, you want to put some effort into making some great icons, so your website looks great on your users' home screen and bookmark section.</description></item><item><title>sudo dnf install beautiful-problems</title><link>https://jugmac00.github.io/blog/sudo-dnf-install-beautiful-problems/</link><pubDate>Wed, 04 Jul 2018 11:16:23 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://jugmac00.github.io/blog/sudo-dnf-install-beautiful-problems/</guid><description>There is something I immediately disliked when using Fedora the first time - the bash prompt.
For many years I&amp;rsquo;ve been using a fixed prompt at work for all my machines, a beauty in green and yellow&amp;hellip;
And when I first started bash after installing Fedora on my home laptop, I encountered this grey monotony&amp;hellip;
[jugmac00@localhost ~]$ I did not try to recreate the prompt I have at work, but I wanted to try something new - and oh my zsh, ah, oh my god, zsh did not come to my mind - yuck!</description></item><item><title>getting back ctrl over ctrl+alt+arrow in gnome</title><link>https://jugmac00.github.io/blog/getting-back-ctrl-over-ctrlaltarrow-keys/</link><pubDate>Sun, 01 Jul 2018 10:47:28 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://jugmac00.github.io/blog/getting-back-ctrl-over-ctrlaltarrow-keys/</guid><description>the task Deactivating Gnome&amp;rsquo;s keyboard shortcuts for ctrl+alt+left / ctrl+alt+right to make those combinations available for another application.
In my case I tried to use these shortcuts in Jetbrain&amp;rsquo;s PyCharm for code navigation.
the obvious (and wrong) way Go to Settings Devices Keyboard Keyboard Shortcuts Change or reset the values for the shortcuts Although both shortcuts are obviously blocked by Gnome, they are not listed.</description></item><item><title>about me</title><link>https://jugmac00.github.io/about/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://jugmac00.github.io/about/</guid><description>I am a software developer with a passion for
Python Linux Open Source I spend a good amount of my spare time
as a maintainer of Flask-Reuploaded as an admirer of tox as a preserver of Morepath as an apprentice of Zope Additionally, I have also contributed to meanwhile more than 300 other open source projects.</description></item><item><title>talks</title><link>https://jugmac00.github.io/talks/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://jugmac00.github.io/talks/</guid><description>Since 2018, I have given many talks at many occasions. I especially enjoy giving lightning and thunder talks.
I want to thank both the Google Developer Group in Regensburg and Python Ireland for giving me a chance to become a more experienced speaker.
May 2021 PyCon US - In &amp;ldquo;How to Maintain Many, Many, Many, Many&amp;hellip; Many Git Repositories?!&amp;rdquo; I walk through the amazing all-repos command line app, and show how to search and grep in many repositories, and finally, how to apply changes to all of them.</description></item></channel></rss>