<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"><channel><title>all-repos on Jürgen Gmach</title><link>https://jugmac00.github.io/tags/all-repos/</link><description>Recent content in all-repos on Jürgen Gmach</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Mon, 19 Apr 2021 11:38:06 +0200</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://jugmac00.github.io/tags/all-repos/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>How Many Zope Repositories Are Compatible With Pypy?</title><link>https://jugmac00.github.io/til/how-many-zope-repositories-are-compatible-with-pypy/</link><pubDate>Mon, 19 Apr 2021 11:38:06 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://jugmac00.github.io/til/how-many-zope-repositories-are-compatible-with-pypy/</guid><description>Today, Johannes Raggam asked on the Plone/Zope community forum whether Zope is able to run on PyPy.
While I am not entirely sure, and I have some vague memories about potential problems with RestrictedPython, I can certainly grep the almost 300 Zope repositories for signs of PyPy support.
The best sign of PyPy support is IMHO that we run tests for it :-)
In order to grep in all repositories I use all-repos written by Anthony Sottile.</description></item><item><title>How to Find All Repositories in a GitHub Organization Which Do Not Follow the Src Layout?</title><link>https://jugmac00.github.io/til/how-to-find-all-repositories-which-do-not-follow-src-layout/</link><pubDate>Fri, 05 Mar 2021 10:49:56 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://jugmac00.github.io/til/how-to-find-all-repositories-which-do-not-follow-src-layout/</guid><description>Let&amp;rsquo;s say, while not everybody is convinced, that the so-called src layout is a great idea, at least it is a trend in the Python eco system.
And, e.g. Hynek has written about good reasons to use the src layout.
While my personal and work repositories (mostly) follow the src layout, what about the almost 300 Zope repositories?
all-repos to the rescue I really love to play with all-repos, an awesome tool to manage and manipulate a large amount of git repositories.</description></item></channel></rss>