<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"><channel><title>bash on Jürgen Gmach</title><link>https://jugmac00.github.io/tags/bash/</link><description>Recent content in bash on Jürgen Gmach</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Wed, 09 Jun 2021 21:54:08 +0200</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://jugmac00.github.io/tags/bash/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>What Is the True Order of Files in a Directory</title><link>https://jugmac00.github.io/til/what-is-the-true-order-of-files-in-a-directory/</link><pubDate>Wed, 09 Jun 2021 21:54:08 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://jugmac00.github.io/til/what-is-the-true-order-of-files-in-a-directory/</guid><description>This week I faced a very odd bug at work.
A build process failed - on one machine, but not on the other.
Of course - identical setup.
The build script consists of a bash script, which wraps a call to the C binary.
The bash script was innocent.
When I had a closer look at the C source code, it turned out there were about 30 lines of code, just dealing with traversing directories and copying files and folders.</description></item><item><title>What Is the Meaning of Dollar Dollar in Bash</title><link>https://jugmac00.github.io/til/what-is-the-meaning-of-dollar-dollar-in-bash/</link><pubDate>Fri, 30 Apr 2021 18:58:07 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://jugmac00.github.io/til/what-is-the-meaning-of-dollar-dollar-in-bash/</guid><description>I stumbled upon a colleague&amp;rsquo;s bash script which contained the following line, which in isolation, made not much sense to me.
WRKDIR=~/app/work$$ But after some googling and having a look at the complete scope of the script, I finally got it.
... WRKDIR=~/app/work$$ ... mkdir $WRKDIR ... ... ... ... rmdir $WRKDIR $$ is a reference to the PID (process id) it was used to create a unique temporary file All good?</description></item><item><title>How to Run a Bash Script in a Sane Way</title><link>https://jugmac00.github.io/til/how-to-run-a-bash-script-in-a-sane-way/</link><pubDate>Thu, 29 Apr 2021 18:48:26 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://jugmac00.github.io/til/how-to-run-a-bash-script-in-a-sane-way/</guid><description>When you never had problems with running/debugging a bash script, you might wonder what I am talking about.
Instead of introducing the possible problems, and then the way to counter them, let&amp;rsquo;s start with the solution.
All your bash scripts should probably start with&amp;hellip;
#!/usr/bin/env bash &amp;hellip; wait&amp;hellip; it goes on&amp;hellip;
set -euxo pipefail Wat? Ok, let&amp;rsquo;s go through the options, one by one.
set -e This makes a bash script to stop on error immediately, and exit.</description></item><item><title>How to Use the Output of One Bash Command as the Argument of Another</title><link>https://jugmac00.github.io/til/how-to-use-the-output-of-one-bash-command-as-the-argument-of-another/</link><pubDate>Mon, 07 Sep 2020 18:52:25 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://jugmac00.github.io/til/how-to-use-the-output-of-one-bash-command-as-the-argument-of-another/</guid><description>TIL my TIL is not secure There is a security issue with the following description - at least when you handle sensitive data.
see here https://github.com/jugmac00/til/commit/7ea93202cecf97070c8931bbe5a1f64c78d41dcb#commitcomment-42050997
Thanks to Anthony Sottile for reporting!
Please see https://unix.stackexchange.com/questions/205180/how-to-pass-password-to-mysql-command-line for a better way to create a login one-liner.
How do you use the output of one bash command as an argument of another command? For the virtual machines at my web hosting company, the mysql root password is stored in a config file.</description></item></channel></rss>