<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"><channel><title>zope on Jürgen Gmach</title><link>https://jugmac00.github.io/tags/zope/</link><description>Recent content in zope on Jürgen Gmach</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Sat, 24 Apr 2021 13:42:58 +0200</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://jugmac00.github.io/tags/zope/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>How to Test Log Output With zope.testrunner</title><link>https://jugmac00.github.io/til/how-to-test-log-output-with-zope-testrunner/</link><pubDate>Sat, 24 Apr 2021 13:42:58 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://jugmac00.github.io/til/how-to-test-log-output-with-zope-testrunner/</guid><description>How to test log output with zope.testrunner? While pytest makes it very easy to work with log files via the caplog fixture, I was not aware how to test them with zope.testrunner, which is used for almost all Zope repositories.
When I asked during yesterday&amp;rsquo;s Zope sprint, I got no answer.
But coincidentally, I stumbled upon a broken doctest which&amp;hellip; tests the log output of a function!
So&amp;hellip; thanks for failing&amp;hellip; I guess :-)</description></item><item><title>How Many Zope Repositories Are Compatible With Pypy?</title><link>https://jugmac00.github.io/til/how-many-zope-repositories-are-compatible-with-pypy/</link><pubDate>Mon, 19 Apr 2021 11:38:06 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://jugmac00.github.io/til/how-many-zope-repositories-are-compatible-with-pypy/</guid><description>Today, Johannes Raggam asked on the Plone/Zope community forum whether Zope is able to run on PyPy.
While I am not entirely sure, and I have some vague memories about potential problems with RestrictedPython, I can certainly grep the almost 300 Zope repositories for signs of PyPy support.
The best sign of PyPy support is IMHO that we run tests for it :-)
In order to grep in all repositories I use all-repos written by Anthony Sottile.</description></item><item><title>What Is the Difference Between Transaction Abort and Transaction Doom</title><link>https://jugmac00.github.io/til/what-is-the-difference-between-transaction-abort-and-transaction-doom/</link><pubDate>Mon, 15 Feb 2021 13:59:42 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://jugmac00.github.io/til/what-is-the-difference-between-transaction-abort-and-transaction-doom/</guid><description>Zope is using the transaction package to manage - you guess - transactions.
More specifically, a transaction starts when Zope receives a request, and the transaction succeeds when the action triggered by the request works out.
When the action causes an exception, the transaction will be rolled back.
This means, usually you very rarely have to interfere with the transaction management manually.
Last week I was implementing a new XML-RPC API, which basically looks like the following code:</description></item><item><title>How to Update All Zope Repositories at Once</title><link>https://jugmac00.github.io/til/how-to-update-all-zope-repositories-at-once/</link><pubDate>Wed, 28 Oct 2020 13:46:51 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://jugmac00.github.io/til/how-to-update-all-zope-repositories-at-once/</guid><description>Most or even all zopefoundation repositories use Travis for CI (As of May 2021, this is no longer true: we use GitHub Actions now).
While Travis offered Python 3.9 as a dev version (3.9-dev) for quite some time, support for 3.9 final took a while.
That&amp;rsquo;s why we decided to run Travis with Python 3.9-dev.
Meanwhile Travis finally offers support for Python 3.9 final, so we have to update all repositories, which would be super tedious by hand.</description></item><item><title>How to Access via WebDav</title><link>https://jugmac00.github.io/til/how-to-access-via-webdav/</link><pubDate>Fri, 09 Oct 2020 13:26:36 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://jugmac00.github.io/til/how-to-access-via-webdav/</guid><description>WebDav is a protocol, based on top of HTTP, that allows clients remote content authoring, such as creating, editing and deleting content.
The protocol itself is pretty old, dating back to the late 90ies.
While not really popular, even modern systems like NextCloud, OwnCloud, and also the widely-used NAS systems by Synology do support this standard - and also Zope!
How to activate WebDav support in Zope? The WebDav support in Zope had been temporarily removed, as Zope switched from the legacy ZServer to the standard WSGI approach, and WebDav was coupled to the ZServer, for no obvious reasons.</description></item><item><title>How to Develop Dependencies With Buildout</title><link>https://jugmac00.github.io/til/how-to-develop-dependencies-with-buildout/</link><pubDate>Mon, 05 Oct 2020 13:33:57 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://jugmac00.github.io/til/how-to-develop-dependencies-with-buildout/</guid><description>Given you have a decent sized project, with some dependencies&amp;hellip;
How can you develop and test a dependency against your main project, when it is not yet published on PyPi?
Well, until recently, I relied on a strong test suite and mostly developed &amp;ldquo;blindly&amp;rdquo;.
When I wanted to see the result, I used Vim to directly edit the dependency in my virtual env.
There must be a better way And actually, there is and has been for more than a decade.</description></item><item><title>How to Setup Zope in Dev Mode</title><link>https://jugmac00.github.io/til/how-to-setup-zope-in-dev-mode/</link><pubDate>Tue, 29 Sep 2020 13:40:28 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://jugmac00.github.io/til/how-to-setup-zope-in-dev-mode/</guid><description>How to setup Zope in development mode? git clone git@github.com:zopefoundation/Zope.git cd Zope python3.8 -m venv .venv . .venv/bin/activate pip install -U pip pip install -e .[wsgi] -c https://zopefoundation.github.io/Zope/releases/master/constraints.txt &amp;hellip; where
-e means editable, ie. developer mode the dot in .[wsgi] means here (similar to cd .. in bash) and [wsgi] means install the wsgi extras, which turns out to be Paste -c adds a constraints file, ie the versions of dependencies get pinned there After the installation, you need to configure Zope before you can run it, cf https://zope.</description></item><item><title>How to Run a Single Test</title><link>https://jugmac00.github.io/til/how-to-run-a-single-test/</link><pubDate>Mon, 28 Sep 2020 13:37:16 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://jugmac00.github.io/til/how-to-run-a-single-test/</guid><description>While this seems to be no Zope specific question, as we all know how to narrow down the test selection with pytest (e.g. pytest -k pattern), Zope does not use pytest, but zope.testrunner.
Similar to pytest, also zope.testrunner offers some command line options, see https://zopetestrunner.readthedocs.io/en/latest/getting-started.html#some-useful-command-line-options-to-get-you-started
This means, in order to run a specific test, you can use the -t flag, which takes one or more regex expressions as input, e.g. -t some_test.</description></item><item><title>How to Replace the Old With the New Decorator Syntax for Zope's Security Declarations</title><link>https://jugmac00.github.io/til/how-to-replace-the-old-with-the-new-decorator-syntax-for-zopes-security-declarations/</link><pubDate>Sat, 11 Apr 2020 13:52:33 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://jugmac00.github.io/til/how-to-replace-the-old-with-the-new-decorator-syntax-for-zopes-security-declarations/</guid><description>Zope&amp;rsquo;s security architecture is built upon security declarations, which scope can be either a method, several methods or even a complete class.
Until recently you usually declared the security for a method like this&amp;hellip;
from AccessControl import getSecurityManager class Suggestions(SomeBaseClass): security = ClassSecurityInfo() security.declareProtected(&amp;#34;View&amp;#34;, &amp;#34;all_suggestions&amp;#34;) def all_suggestions(): ... Then, when accessing this method, e.g. the logged in user&amp;rsquo;s role or group was checked against the security declaration.
One big disadvantage was that you could easily introduce typos.</description></item></channel></rss>